FATIH ARI

Aspiring New Developer | Powercoders Participant

Aarhaldenstrasse 6, 3052 Zollikofen | * 25.06.1982 | Residence permit B fatih.ari@powercoders.org | +41 77 999 43 97

GitHub | Learning Blog | LinkedIn

Languages: English (B2), German (B2), Turkish (mother tongue)

IT skills: Beginner: Angular 2+, Testing

Elementary: HTML, CSS, React, SQL

Spring Framework 5, IntelliJ

Intermediate: Java, JavaScript, Git, GitHub, Agile (Scrum)



SUMMARY

I am an experienced Mechanical Engineer with 11 years engineering and project managing experience in different sectors. I am also self-learning web engineering disciplines for a year as an alternative profession. I have a passion for learning IT technologies to go further in this way.

WORK EXPERIENCE

02/2017 - 08/2018

Manager of the Production Unit, HYT Group, Ankara-Turkey

- Assigning employees and Task control
- Tracking of orders and quality control of products
- Ensuring all communication in the importation of ventilation units from abroad
- Catalog preparation
- Employee selection and placement

09/2016 - 01/2017

Mechanical Engineer, HYT Group, Ankara-Turkey

- Working on the "Sheet Metal Bending Machine" and "Cutting Machine"
- Programming the "CNC Plasma Cutting Machine"
- Designing of ventilation units via 3D design softwares
- Working on installation of ventilation equipments

02/2012 - 07/2016

Project Manager/ Deputy Director,

Banknote Printing Plant of Central Bank of Turkey, Ankara-Turkey

- Feasibility studies of machinery and equipment to be procured
- Specification document preparation and technical support during the tender phase
- To carry out joint studies and projects with Universities
- Managing 5 different projects from concept design to production
- Projection of some products with the method of reverse engineering and producing by working with domestic companies.
- Representation of Banknote Printing Plant in international and domestic conferences and events; with realization of the necessary presentation works

12/2006 - 02/2012

Mechanical Engineer,

Banknote Printing Plant of Central Bank of Turkey, Ankara-Turkey

- Planning and control of periodical maintenance of printing machines
- Communication with overseas suppliers and providing the necessary spare parts and materials
- Technical drawings of spare parts
- Domestically supply in cases where procurement from abroad is not appropriate
- Creating and updating internal standards and tools (ISO Processes, ERP Processes etc.)

EDUCATION

09/2020 - 12/2020

Powercoders - Coding Academy for Refugees, Zurich, Switzerland

- Foundations in HTML, CSS, JavaScript; specialization tracks upcoming
- Weekly business & social skills training (teamwork, communication, etc.)

01/2019 - 12/2019

IT Club Oberland -Zürich, Switzerland

- Web programming basics
- Programming with Java and Spring framework

01/2020 - 07/2020

Guest Student, Bern Fachhochschule/Industrial Engineering and Management, Biel/Bienne, Switzerland

- Supply chain and logistics management
- Basic study about Industry 4.0
- Concept design of a product to produce in CP Factory
- Conceptual adaptation of Industry 4.0 Lab.

09/2014 –

Master of Business Administration, Gazi University, Ankara, Turkey

 Uncompleted Thesis: "Awareness of the Banknotes: The objective and subjective knowledge of Users on Discriminating Fake Banknotes" (I have successfully completed all the courses and exams, but I could not complete the master's thesis due to personal political problems)

09/2005 - 08/2008

M.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey

 Master Thesis: "Design And Production Of A Welding Robot " İstanbul-2008 / Supervisor: Prof. Dr.Bülent EKİCİ

09/2000 - 06/2005

BA in Mechanical Engineering, Marmara University, Istanbul, Turkey

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

02/2020 - Present Volunteer, Zollikofe-Mitenang, 3052-Zollikofen

- Supporting the residents of Zollikofen in the old people's centre or at home with various activities in everyday life.

CERTIFICATION

04/2020	Java Programming: Arrays, Lists, and Structured Data by Duke University on
	Coursera.
01/2020	Agile with Atlassian Jira by Atlassian on Coursera.
01/2020	Java Programming: Solving Problems with Software by Duke University on
	Coursera
01/2020	Visual Elements of User Interface Design by California Institute of the Arts on
	Coursera.

HOBBIES

Travelling, cycling and table tennis

REFERENCES

- Hussam Allaham, Powercoders Industry Lead, hussam.allaham@powercoders.org,
 +41 77 906 16 27
- Ebubekir Kaya, General Manager, International Language School, info@ils-bern.ch , +41 31 556 35 89
- Louis Amport, German Tandem Support, Hiphop Center Bern, <u>l.amport@hiphopcenter.ch</u>, +41 31 511 21 14 (Mon. 14:00-19:00 / Wed. 13:00-16:00)